《超感警探》前情提要
Previously on "The mentalist"...
我們得找到基拉·汀斯利
We need to find kira tinsley.
她要么跟血腥約翰是一伙的
She either works for Red John,
要么馬上就要成為他下一個目標了
or she's about to become his next victim.
誰干的  告訴我
Who did this to you? Tell me.
簡  她說什么了
Jane, what did she say?
她說血腥約翰左肩膀有個紋身
She told me Red John has a tattoo on his left shoulder--
三個點
Three dots.
這是我的籌碼
That's my leverage.
馬里布
加利福尼亞  馬里布  簡的住宅
-簡  -喂  里斯本
- Jane. - Hello, Lisbon.
簡  別這么做  別扔下我這么做
Jane, don't do this, not without me.
對不起
Listen, I'm sorry.
簡  求你了  你身處險境
Jane, I am begging you. You're in danger!
沒事的  我不會有事的
I-it's gonna be okay. I-I'm gonna be okay.
不可能
No, you're not.
你這樣做是在自尋死路
You do this, and you're throwing your life away.
再見  里斯本
Bye, Lisbon.
簡  別這樣
Jane... no.
人人影視
YYeTs.com
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
■
僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為
更多影視更新
請登陸www.YYeTs.com
■
翻譯：灰灰是菇涼  Michael  王小麥  莎友友  小早  靜靜的木頭  那時花開
超感警探
第六季
第六集
■
時間軸：Sagelibra  兜兜兜爹   校對：灰灰是菇涼
第六季
第六集
■
特效&后期：灰灰是菇涼   精校&總監：灰灰是菇涼
兩天前
星期二
紋身嗎
A tattoo?
對
Yes.
我們可以用那個來確定血腥約翰的身份
That we can use to identify Red John?
-是的  -太好了
- Yes. - That's great.
所以我們只要一個個檢查疑犯
So all we have to do is check each one of the suspects
看哪個人身上就紋身就行了
one by one until we find out who has the tattoo.
不行
No.
為什么不行
Why not?
血腥約翰還不知道我發現紋身的事
Red John doesn't know I know about the tattoo.
好吧
Okay.
所以如果我們去查他們
So if we start checking suspects,
很有可能血腥約翰會發現此事
it's very likely that red john will find out.
然后在我們還沒機會接近他的時候就銷聲匿跡
And disappear before we have a chance of getting him.
正是如此
Exactly.
那你們打算怎么辦
Then what do you want to do?
把五名疑犯同時
Gather all five suspects together
集合到一個地方
at the same place, same time,
然后再檢查是否有紋身
And then start checking for the tattoo.
如何才能做到呢
And how do we do that?
就直接叫他們過來
We'll ask them.
你覺得他們會同意嗎
And you think they'll agree?
沒打算給他們選擇的余地
Wasn't planning on giving them a choice.
就算成行了  還有個問題
Even so, there's a problem.
布萊特·斯特爾斯因兩起謀殺
Bret Stiles--he's wanted by the F.B.I.
被聯調局通緝
in connection to two homicides.
對  二十多年前的懸案
Yeah. Cold cases from over 20 years ago.
真的假的
You're kidding,
都過去那么多年了
after all this time,
聯調局現在才跟進嗎
the F.B.I. is moving in now?
他們肯定是有了什么新的
Well, they must have found something new--
-法醫證據  目擊證人  -那斯特爾斯在哪
- forensics, a witness. Well, where's Stiles?
關鍵就是這個  沒人知道他在哪
Well, that's the thing. Nobody knows,
連聯調局也不知道  斯特爾斯幾周前就消失了
Not even the F.B.I. Stiles disappeared weeks ago.
我們會找到他的
We'll find him.
怎么找
How?
不知道  但我們會找到他的
I don't know, but we'll find him.
必須找到他
We have to.
我配合你的計劃
I'm on board with your plan.
好
Good.
有個條件
On one condition.
你揭露血腥約翰身份的時候我要在場
I want to be there when you reveal Red John.
好的
Okay.
我說真的
Seriously.
-我說了好的  -說是說了  但你說的肯定不算數
- I said okay. - Yeah, but you didn't mean it.
是嗎  你怎么知道
Did I not? Uh, how can you tell?
這事沒有商量的余地  簡
This is non-negotiable, Jane.
我百分百同意
I agree 100%.
我認為我之前說得夠清楚了  探員們
I think I've made myself clear, agents.
我完全不知道布萊特·斯特爾斯在哪
I have no knowledge of Bret Stiles' whereabouts.
對  你說了
Yes,
而我們也表達得很清楚了  你這說法我們不買賬
and we've made it clear that we're not buying it.
斯特爾斯把天眼組織的領導權留給了你
Stiles leaves you in charge of Visualize,
但他卻沒有告訴你他躲藏在哪里嗎
but he keeps you in the dark about where he's hiding?
這根本說不通
Doesn't make sense.
斯特爾斯自始至終
Stiles has and always will
都將教徒的需要放在他自己之前
put the church's needs before his own.
這次也一樣
This time is no different.
他不想讓我知道是因為他想保護我
He doesn't want me to know because he wants to protect me.
也因為他不想被人找到
And because he doesn't want to be found.
我不覺得布萊特·斯特爾斯擔心是否會被找到
I doubt Bret Stiles is worried about being found.
你看起來很有信心
You seem confident.
這叫信仰
Call it faith.
斯特爾斯在我們這個
You see, Stiles' time
現實世界里的時間  是有限的
in our... reality is limited.
就在我們說話的這會
As we speak,
他正在做好心理和身體上的準備
he's preparing his mind and body
以擺脫我們這個物質世界的束縛
for a departure from the confines of our material world.
他要死了嗎
He's dying?
這是非常天真
That is a very naive,
非常無知的想法
very ignorant way of looking at it.
布萊特·斯特爾斯不會死
Bret Stiles is not dying.
他也不能死
Bret Stiles cannot die.
他是要將自己提升到一個新的高度
He is elevating himself to another plane,
我們這種道行不夠的
one lesser men like ourselves
要非常艱難才能觸碰到這種高度
can only strive to reach.
顯然我們中有人對此是無法理解的
And one some of us obviously can't comprehend.
咖啡  加了一份奶油  一份糖
Coffee--one cream, one sugar.
謝了  拉塞爾
Thanks, Russell.
你要準備好了的話鑒證小組就要過來了
Forensics is here when you're ready.
讓他們過來吧
Send them over.
幫我查明他的身份  好嗎
Get his I.D. for me, will you?
你知道我怕高
You know how I am about heights.
沒問題
Sure.
對了  有人來找你
Oh, and, uh, someone's here to see you.
謝了
Thanks.
血腥約翰的案子有了重大突破
There's been a breakthrough in the Red John investigation.
我得到了一些新線索
I have some new information.
非常重要的線索
Some very significant information.
好吧  是什么
Okay. What is it?
不  現在還不能說
No, no. Not yet.
我不知道能信任誰
I'm not sure who I can trust.
我甚至不知道能不能信任你
I'm not even sure I can trust you.
血腥約翰有一些位高權重的同伙
Red John has some very powerful allies.
派翠克  不是吧
Patrick, come on.
好吧  但不能在這說
Okay, but not here.
周四晚上八點見面
Meet me at 8:00 on Thursday night.
周四  為什么
Thursday? Why?
我需要時間找一個安全的見面地點
I need time to find a safe place to meet.
好吧  在哪見
Fine. Where?
等到了那天再告訴你
I'll let you know the day of.
太扯淡了
This is crazy.
我已經犯過很多次錯誤了
I've made the mistake of underestimating Red John
總是低估了血腥約翰
a number of times now.
我不想再犯這種錯誤了
I don't want to make that mistake again.
如果你想知道線索  就要聽我的
If you want the information, it's on my terms.
好吧
Okay.
周四晚上
Thursday night.
我是麥卡利斯特警長
This is Sheriff McAllister.
警長嗎  我是派翠克·簡
Sheriff? Patrick Jane.
你好  派翠克  最近怎么樣
Hello, Patrick. How are things?
很好  很好
Good. Good.
-我打電話是有事想問你  -問吧
- I'm calling because I had a question. - Shoot.
上個月我去納帕谷的時候
Last month when I was in Napa,
你說聽任我的調遣
you said that you were at my disposal.
是的  我記得
Yes, I remember.
你說話算數嗎
Did you mean what you said?
我覺得我是講信用的人
I like to think I'm a man of my word.
絕對是
Oh, I don't doubt it.
但我能指望你幫我個忙嗎
But can I count on you for your help?
可以嗎
Can I count on you?
當然
Of course.
周四晚上八點我需要你的幫助
Thursday night at 8:00 I'll need your help.
沒問題
Well, then you've got it.
謝謝
Thank you.
等到那天我再告訴你去哪
I'll let you know where to be the day of.
派翠克
Patrick?
什么事
Yeah?
是關于血腥約翰的事  對吧
This is about Red John, isn't it?
周四晚上見
Thursday night.
他們準備好了  先生
They're ready for you, sir.
謝謝你  伊夫林
Thank you, Evelyn.
還有  這是給您的
Also, this came for you.
派翠克·簡正在找你
今晚你們在這里
You are here tonight
將見證我升天
to witness my ascension.
從這個世界  飛升到
My ascension from this world
一個世外的天地
to a world beyond.
不要為我哀悼  我的子民
Do not mourn me, my children,
因為這并非逝去
for this is not a passing,
而是啟程
but a departure.
我保證
And I promise...
我  將
I... will...
歸來
return!
星期三
聽我說  唐  你養的不是一個情婦
Listen to me, Don, you don't have a mistresst.
那只是一個想要報復你  會毀掉你的瘋子
You have a vindictive screwball who's about to ruin your life.
你該慶幸
Yes, well, it's very lucky for you
我的工作就是解決問題  你現在要做的是
my job is to fix problems, so here's what you're gonna do.
你要給她開張支票
You are gonna write her a check--
給她很大一筆錢
It is gonna be a very big check--
然后祈禱這事就這么完了
And then you are gonna pray that this problem goes away.
如果還沒完  也別擔心  唐
If it doesn't, don't worry, Don.
有很多種辦法可以讓一個女人閉嘴  別擔心
There are plenty of ways to keep a woman quiet, OK?
好了
All right.
我掛了
I gotta go. All right.
你遲到了
You're late.
我也很高興見到你  特蕾莎
It's good to see you, too, Teresa.
你好  請給我來一杯黑咖
Uh, excuse me, can I get coffee, black, please?
謝謝
Thanks.
早上八點把我叫來干什么
So why am I here at 8:00 a.m.?
我有個調查需要你的幫助
I need help with an investigation.
什么調查
What investigation?
這不重要
It's not important.
是么  如果你找我幫忙那這就很重要
Really? It is if you want my help.
我不能告訴你
I can't tell you.
得了吧  特蕾莎  我還不了解你嗎
Come on, Teresa. I know you better than that.
你和簡對血腥約翰的調查
What, you and Jane got something going on
有進展了吧
with the Red John case?
也許吧
Maybe.
"也許"  是啊
"Maybe." Yeah, right.
為什么要搞得這么神秘
What is with all the secrecy?
說真的  為什么要瞞著我
Seriously, why are you always holding out on me?
你們該不會覺得我是血腥約翰吧
You don't think I'm Red John, do you?
你們就是這么想的  是嗎
You do, don't you?
聽著
Tell you what.
你要想找我問話  那就逮捕我
You want to question me, you arrest me.
否則就別把我扯進來
Otherwise, you leave me the hell out of this.
坐下
Sit down.
坐
Sit.
如果問不管用  我不問了
If asking's not gonna work, I won't ask.
你已經不為加調局工作了
You're no longer with the CBI.
你現在無法得到執法人員所能得到的保護了
You don't get the same protection law enforcement gets.
-怎么  你威脅我  -不是我  是簡
- What, you threatening me? - No, Jane is.
他明天晚上想見你一面
He wants to see you tomorrow night.
你如果不去  他就會認為你是血腥約翰
If you don't show up, he will assume you're Red John.
然后他會找你麻煩的  雷
And, Ray, he will come after you.
你開玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
你了解簡的  你知道他身上發生了什么
You know Jane. You know what happened to him.
你也知道血腥約翰對他做了些什么
You know what Red John did to him.
如果是我  我不會拿這個試探他
If I were you, I wouldn't test him.
我可不怕派翠克·簡
I'm not afraid of Patrick Jane.
那去和他見一面又有什么關系
Well, what's the problem with showing up?
我如果去了  你和簡
If I do this, will you and Jane drop
就不會再懷疑我是血腥約翰了嗎
the whole that "I'm Red John" business?
以后絕對不會了
For once and for all.
什么時間
What time?
八點
08:00.
我還沒說完
I'm not done.
還有件事
There's one more thing that I need.
殺了我算了
You're killing me here.
-斯特爾斯  -他怎么了
- Stiles. - Yeah?
-他在哪兒  -我幫不了你
- Where is he? - I can't help you.
得了吧  雷
Come on, Ray,
你都為天眼組織工作這么多年了
you've been with Visualize for years.
我不想抓他  我只想跟他談談
I don't want to arrest him. I just want to talk to him.
你幫我這個忙  算我欠你的
You do this, and I will owe you.
你現在在做的事
And in your line of work,
遲早你會需要我幫忙的
sooner or later you're gonna need a favor.
雷·哈弗內說斯特爾斯
So Ray Haffner told me that Stiles uses
有一架私人飛機供其往來國內不被發現
a private jet to move around the country undetected.
機主是一個名叫萊恩·帕克斯的人
Belongs to a guy named Ryan Parks.
帕克斯  知道了  我去查
Parks. Got it. I'll check it out.
簡到局里了嗎
Has Jane been in yet?
還沒
No, I haven't heard from him.
加州  帕羅奧多  帕羅奧多機場
拉莫特先生嗎
Mr. Lamotte?
是我  有什么可效勞的
Yeah? Can I help you?
周探員  瑞斯比探員  加調局的
Agents Cho and Rigsby from the CBI.
我們想請你回答幾個問題
We were wondering if you could answer a few questions for us.
好的
Sure.
昨晚有一架G6私人飛機降落在這里
A G6 landed here late last night,
注冊尾號為M550MT
tail number M550MT.
大約十一點左右
It would have been around 11:00.
我記得  怎么了
I remember. What about it?
你知道飛機上的人是誰嗎
Do you know who was on the flight?
不知道  私人飛機不需要
No. Private aircraft aren't required
提供乘客名單
to provide passenger manifests.
你有碰巧見到有誰從飛機上下來嗎
Did you happen to see anyone who was getting off the plane?
沒有  抱歉
No. Sorry.
不過  有汽車服務公司的人來接他
Oh, but whoever it was had a car service pick him up.
他們可能幫得上忙
They might be able to help you.
你不會正好知道那個汽車服務公司的名字吧
You don't happen to have the name of that car service, by any chance?
知道
Yes, I do.
汽車服務公司那邊怎么說
So what happened with the car service?
他們說昨晚從機場接到了一個
Well, they said that they picked up a silver-haired man
操著英國口音的銀發男人
with a British accent from the airport last night.
-斯特爾斯  -我們也是這么想的
- Stiles. - We think so.
那他去哪了
Well, where'd he go?
地址是厄瓜多爾領事館
The address was for the Ecuadorian Consulate
在舊金山
in San Francisco.
好樣的  你們倆去查查看
Good job. You two go and check it out.
我說  范佩爾  不如你一個人去吧
You know what? Van Pelt, why don't you go alone?
斯特爾斯喜歡你
Stiles likes you.
也許我們能利用這個優勢
Maybe we can use that to our advantage.
有什么問題嗎
Is...there a problem?
-沒有  -沒有
- Uh, no. - No.
-我沒問題的  -我知道
- I'll be fine. - I know.
-職責所在  -我知道
- It's my job. - I know.
我愛你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
里斯本
Hey, Lisbon.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我就干點跑腿的活
Oh, just running some errands.
一切都好嗎
Everything okay?
好極了  有事嗎
Yeah, right as rain. What's up?
哈弗內答應了
Haffner's in.
很好  斯特爾斯那邊怎樣了
Good. What about Stiles?
范佩爾好像瞄準他的位置了
Van Pelt may have a bead on his location.
她正在查
She's checking it out now.
這樣就還剩一個血腥約翰案疑犯要約談
That leaves one more Red John suspect left to talk to.
是的  伯特侖  我正往他辦公室走呢
Yes. Bertram. I'm on my way to his office.
-咱們那邊見嗎  -好
- You want to meet me there? - All right.
加利福尼亞  舊金山  厄瓜多爾領事館
格蕾斯·范佩爾
Grace Van Pelt.
再次見到你真是太好了
Well...how lovely to see you again.
請坐吧
Well...so, please sit.
這次有何貴干呢
What do I owe this pleasure?
是簡
Jane.
他需要你幫個忙
He needs a favor.
差你來  他可真聰明
Oh. Clever, him, sending you.
那么我到底能為派翠克·簡做些什么呢
So exactly what can I do for Patrick Jane?
他想見見你
He would like to meet with you.
明天晚上八點
Tomorrow night at 8:00.
自我們上次一別  你變樣了
You've changed since we last met.
你結婚了
You're married.
是的
Yes.
別跟我說你嫁給那個只會傻笑的呆子了
Oh, don't tell me you married that genial oaf.
好吧  恭喜你
Oh. Oh, well. Congratulations.
謝謝你
Yeah. Thank you.
那么  你會去見簡嗎
So...will you meet with Jane?
你知道的
Ah...you know,
能見他我再高興不過了
nothing would please me more than to meet with him.
我真的很樂意  但是
I mean, really, I would love to. But...
很不幸的是  鑒于我現在的境況
unfortunately, my circumstances--
好像不太能成行
it's probably not gonna happen.
你是說因為聯邦調查局嗎
You mean because of the F.B.I.?
你功課做得不錯嘛
Mm. You have been doing your homework.
他們不知道我來了
They don't know I'm here.
所以他們也就不知道你在這里
Which means they don't know you're here.
但你要是不肯見簡  他們就會知道了
But they will if you don't agree to meet with Jane.
你的確變了  不是嗎
You have changed, haven't you?
你去過厄瓜多爾嗎
Have you ever been to Ecuador, by any chance?
沒有
No.
我很多很多年以前
I was there--oh, god, years and years ago
在那傳教來著
doing missionary work. Uh...
那里的人很不錯
lovely people.
不過有個年輕人
But there was a young man there...
他很窮  但野心勃勃
he was underprivileged, ferociously ambitious.
我在他身上看到了些東西
I saw something in him.
所以我決定試著幫幫他
So I decided to try and help him.
我幫他付學費
You know, I-I paid for his school fees,
之類的
that sort of thing.
其實也沒什么  但你猜怎么著
N-nothing really much, but wouldn't you know it?
這么多年之后
All these years later,
那小子已經是國務部長了
that same man is now Minister of State.
我很為他高興
I'm happy for him.
他邀請我住在這豪華的領事館里
Anyway, he invited me to stay in this palatial consulate.
在這一片小小的外國領土上
This morsel of foreign soil.
外國領土  如你所知
Foreign soil, of which, as you know,
是不受你們加調局  聯調局
is outside the jurisdiction of you, the F.B.I.,
與任何美國法律管轄的
or U.S. law enforcement.
所以呢  格蕾斯  你的威脅不管用
So, you see, Gracie, your idle threats are just that.
當然  很高興能再見到你
Well, it's been so lovely seeing you again.
幫我跟簡問個好
Please give my best to Mr. Jane.
出去的時候隨手關門
Close the door on your way out!
沒事的
It's gonna be fine.
謝謝啊  我感覺輕松多了
Thanks. I feel a lot better.
進來
Come on in.
長官  案子有突破了
We've made a breakthrough, sir.
-什么案子  -血腥約翰案
- In... - The Red John case.
我們馬上就能確定兇手了
We're close to identifying him.
真是個好消息
Well, then this is fantastic news.
都這么多年了
After all these years. Y-you--
你真的確定了嗎
You really think you've got him?
是的
I do.
一旦你們有了切實答案要立刻告訴我
I'll know the second you have something concrete.
是的  長官
You will, sir.
此案結束的時候我要在場
And I want to be there when you end this.
就等您這句話呢
I was hoping you'd say that.
喂  是我
Yeah, it's me.
我剛和派翠克·簡談了點有趣的事
I just had a very interesting conversation with Patrick Jane.
伯特侖那邊怎么樣
How'd it go with Bertram?
上鉤了  斯特爾斯那邊呢
He's in. What about Stiles?
-不太好  -你找到他了嗎
- Not so good. - Did you find him?
找到了
Yes.
那還有什么問題
Then what's the problem?
他住在厄瓜多爾領事館里
He's at the Ecuadorian consulate.
只要他在里面  我們就動不了他
As long as he's there, we can't touch him.
你打算怎么辦
What do you want to do?
我來對付斯特爾斯
I'll handle Stiles.
他不會也不必跟你出來
He's not gonna come with you. He doesn't have to.
相信我的說服力
I'll be persuasive.
那是什么
What is that?
霰彈槍
A shot gun?
火力夠大了嗎
You sure it's big enough?
關于明天晚上的事  我們得談談
We need to talk about tomorrow night.
我已經告訴你了
I've already told you.
先聽我說完
Just hear me out, please.
你不希望我在場
You don't want me to be there.
是的
No, I don't.
你不希望我在場是因為你覺得
You don't want to be there because you think
我會阻止你殺血腥約翰
I'm gonna try and stop you from killing red john.
你的意思是你不會嗎
Are you saying that you won't?
我想說的是
What I'm saying is some men--
像血腥約翰這種禽獸
men like Red John--
根本連上庭受審的資格都沒有
they don't deserve a trial. They don't deserve a jury.
這種人就該就地正法
They deserve what they have coming to them.
等等  讓我搞搞清楚
Wait, l-let me get this straight.
你在執法部門干了快二十年
After close to 20 years working in law enforcement,
竟然就這么改變原則了嗎
you're just-- you're changing your mind?
在血腥約翰案上嗎  沒錯
About Red John? Yes.
我很驚訝  里斯本
I'm surprised, Lisbon.
怎么  你不相信我嗎
What, you don't believe me?
當然不會
Heavens, no.
你是我認識的最誠實的人
You're the most honest person I know.
這種事情上  你絕不會騙我的
You would never lie, not about something like this.
是不是
Right?
當然
Right.
那明晚見
Tomorrow night then.
明晚見
Tomorrow night.
星期四
派翠克  我親愛的孩子
Patrick, dear boy.
近來還好嗎
Well, how are you?
我不是你的孩子
Well, I'm not your boy.
我明白了  那么說你不是來找我聊天的
Oh, I see. So this is not a social meeting, eh?
明晚八點你要來見我
You're gonna meet me tonight at 8:00.
-派翠克  -不  你聽我說
- Patrick. - No, you listen to me.
我要你明晚八點來見我
You're gonna meet me tonight at 8:00,
否則等到我再回來找你
Or I'm gonna come back here, and when I do,
就算這是領事館也保不了你
you will need more than these walls to keep you safe.
威脅我嗎
Threats?
這不是你的風格啊
That's so out of character.
我說的話句句當真
I mean every word of it.
確實
Yes.
我相信你
I believe you do.
可是派翠克
But you see, Patrick,
將死之人還怕什么死亡威脅呢
a dying man does not fear death.
省省吧
Oh, please.
裝模作樣騙騙你那些信徒還行
This charade might work on your disciples.
騙我就算了吧
It doesn't work on me.
你太高估我了
You think too highly of me.
非常不幸的是
Unfortunately,
這次不是裝的了
it's not a charade.
你還剩多長時間
How long have you got?
已經擴散到血液了
It's spread to the blood.
已經無藥可醫了  我不知道
There's nothing they can do. I don't know...
也許兩周  也許一個月
Two weeks, a month.
聽我說
You see...
這不是針對你
it's not personal.
只是現在
It's just that...
時間對我來說太寶貴了
my time now is very precious.
今晚我還是需要你來
I'm still gonna need you tonight.
看在上帝的份上  為什么
For god sake, why?
有什么事如此重要
What's so damned important?
血腥約翰
Red John.
我終于接近他了
I'm close.
前所未有的接近
Closer than I've ever been.
血腥約翰
Red John...
聽著
Look...
今晚我若能去見你
nothing would give me more pleasure
那是再高興不過了
than to be with you there tonight.
但是
But?
我的情況比你想象的復雜
There's more to this than you know.
我被困在這兒還有別的原因
There's--there's more keeping me here.
聯調局嗎
The F.B.I?
對  事實正是如此
Yeah, as a matter of fact.
他們跟我到這里
You know, they tracked me here.
就等著我出去
They're just waiting for me to leave
然后逮捕我
so they can arrest me.
不是我想呆在這兒的
Look, I'm not choosing to stay here,
我被困住了
but I'm trapped.
這么說聯調局是唯一的問題了
So the F.B.I's the only thing that's keeping you here?
注意  前門有動靜
Eyes up, we've got movement at the front entry.
是天眼組織的車
That's a Visualize car.
他們在偷偷往外轉移什么人
I think they're sneaking someone out.
隨時準備行動
Get ready to move.
立即行動  行動  上
Go now! Go! Go! Go!
-不許動  -不許動
- Don't move! - Don't move!
把手放在方向盤上
Hands on your steering wheel!
把手放在我們能看見的地方
Keep your hands where we can see 'em.
你們好  先生們
Hello. Gentlemen.
有什么能為你們效勞的嗎
Something I can help you with?
斯特爾斯入局了
Stiles is in.
我們該出發了
We'd better get going.
我們可有很長一段車程
We've got a long drive ahead of us.
把他帶走
Take him.
晚上八點  馬里布  雪松街1309號見  走便道
信息已發送
那么薩城警局只有等著了
Well, then Sac P.D.'s just gonna have to wait.
我不想用職權壓人
Look, I-I don't wanna pull rank...
但若有必要我會的
but I will.
凱文  回頭我再打給你
Kevin, I gotta call you back.
我需要一輛車
I'll be needing a car.
我們要去干什么
What are we doing?
我想看看日落
I want to see the sunset.
里斯本  有些話我想跟你說
There's something I want to tell you, Lisbon.
很早以前就應該跟你說了
Something I should have said a long time ago.
謝謝你做的一切
I want to thank you for everything that you've done.
晚點再謝也不遲
You can thank me later.
不
No, I...
我必須現在就說
I need to say this now.
你
You have...
不知道你對我意味著什么
no idea what you've meant to me.
你對我有多重要
What you mean to me.
謝謝你
Thank you.
差點忘了  我有個驚喜給你
I almost forgot. I have a surprise for you.
在這等我
Wait here.
簡
Jane?
Jane!
馬里布
加利福尼亞  馬里布  簡的住宅
停車
Hey! Stop!
請等等
Please.
我叫特蕾莎·里斯本
My name is Teresa Lisbon.
我是加州調查局探員
I am an agent with the California Bureau of Investigation,
現在我要征用你的車
and I need to borrow your car.
這是緊急情況
It's an emergency.
什么  不行
What?! No way.
立即下車  快
Get out. Now. Come on.
快
Come on.
太過分了
This is outrageous.
我要報警
I'm calling the police.
好主意  謝謝
Good idea. Thanks.
-簡  -喂  里斯本
- Jane. - Hello, Lisbon.
簡  別這么做  別扔下我這么做
Jane, don't do this, not without me.
對不起
Listen, I'm sorry.
簡  求你了  你身處險境
Jane, I am begging you. You're in danger!
沒事的
I-it's gonna be okay.
我不會有事的
I-I'm gonna be okay.
不可能
No, you're not.
你這樣做是在自尋死路
You do this, and you're throwing your life away.
再見  里斯本
Bye, Lisbon.
簡
Jane...
別這樣
No.
你好  派翠克
Oh. Hello, Patrick.
我來早了嗎
Am I early?
不早  來得正好  坐吧
No, no. Right on time. Have a seat.
911  您遇到了什么緊急情況
9-1-1. What's your emergency?
我是加州調查局的
This is Agent Teresa Lisbon
特蕾莎·里斯本探員
with the California Bureau of Investigation.
請派警員到馬里布的雪松街1309號
I need officers at 1309 Cedar Street in Malibu.
有探員需要立即支援
I have an agent who needs immediate assistance.
我讓你們五個聚在一起是有原因的
I brought you five together for a reason.
有人可能知道了
Some of you may know that reason.
也有人可能猜到了
Some of you may have guessed.
你們中的一個人
But one of you here...
是血腥約翰
is Red John.
什么  在我們幾個中間
What?! One of us?
我們其中之一是血腥約翰
One of us here is Red John?
真有意思
Well, that's very interesting.
-是誰  -我不知道
- Who is it? - I don't know.
我們到這來就是為了找出答案
And that's what we're gonna find out.
你是想說這個房間里的某個人
Wait, you're trying to say that one of us in this room...
是個連環殺手
is a serial killer?
-我很確定  -太荒唐了
- I know it. - No, this is crazy.
我向你保證完全不荒唐
I can assure you it's not.
我向你保證  我才不跟你在這兒胡鬧
Well, I can assure you I'm not sticking around for this crap.
坐下
Sit down.
一步都別想往門口走
Do not move toward the door.
誰都不準走
No one is leaving.
放輕松  派翠克
Take it easy, Patrick.
我看起來很緊張嗎
Do I look distressed?
別動
Don't.
我會開槍的
I will shoot you.
其他人也一樣
That goes for the rest of you as well.
慢慢把你們的槍拿出來  放在地上
Take out your weapons slowly, place them on the floor,
推到我這邊來
and push them toward me.
謝謝
Thank you.
行了  派翠克
Okay, Patrick.
夠了
This is... this is enough.
該到此為止了
It's gone far enough.
不  這才剛剛開始呢
No, we're just getting started.
為這一刻  我等了十年
I've waited ten years for this moment.
多年來  血腥約翰一直很狡猾
All those years, Red John has been smart.
你們中的某個人一直很狡猾
One of you has been smart.
很謹慎  除了這次
Careful. But not this time.
這一次  你露出馬腳了
This time, you made a mistake.
基拉·汀斯利死之前跟我說了件事
Kira Tinsley told me something before she passed.
她告訴我殺她的人  也就是血腥約翰
She told me that her killer-- Red John--
有個紋身
has a tattoo.
左臂上有三個點
Three dots on his left arm.
就在肩膀上
On the shoulder.
你們都得
And you all...
給我看
are gonna show me...
立刻動手
Now.
開始脫吧  快
Let's go. Come on.
對了  脫掉
That's it. Take it off.
太荒唐了
Nonsense.
很好
Very good.
不是你想得那樣
It's not what you think.
-你弄錯了  -住嘴
- You got it wrong. - Enough.
我不是血腥約翰
I'm not Red John.
派翠克  等等  派翠克
Patrick, wait. Patrick!
看  這邊
Look... here.
看
Look.
站起來
On your feet.
到他們倆那邊去
Over with those two.
你們別動
You stay there.
好了  你們三個
Okay, you three...
到墻邊站著  快
Over against that wall-- now.
等等  不要
Wait! No!
馬里布
簡
Jane!